&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HeadlessCMS on HugoPaper</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/tags/headlesscms/</link><description>Recent content in HeadlessCMS on HugoPaper</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 16:55:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugopaper.github.io/tags/headlesscms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Do I Develop My Portfolio Website &amp; Blog</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/examples/how-do-i-develop-my-portfolio-and-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 16:55:12 +0000</pubDate><author>Sat Naing</author><guid>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/examples/how-do-i-develop-my-portfolio-and-blog/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is originally from my &lt;a href="https://satnaing.dev/blog/posts/how-do-i-develop-my-portfolio-and-blog"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;. I put this article to demonstrate how you can write blog posts/articles using AstroPaper theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience about developing my first portfolio website and a blog using NextJS and a headless CMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://satnaing.dev/_ipx/w_2048,q_75/https%3A%2F%2Fres.cloudinary.com%2Fnoezectz%2Fimage%2Fupload%2Fv1653050141%2FSatNaing%2Fblog_at_cafe_ei1wf4.jpg?url=https%3A%2F%2Fres.cloudinary.com%2Fnoezectz%2Fimage%2Fupload%2Fv1653050141%2FSatNaing%2Fblog_at_cafe_ei1wf4.jpg&amp;amp;w=2048&amp;amp;q=75" alt="Building portfolio"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="motivation"&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been always thinking about launching my own website with my custom domain name (&lt;strong&gt;satnaing.dev&lt;/strong&gt;) since my college student life. But that never happened until this project. I&amp;rsquo;ve done several projects and works about web application development but I didn&amp;rsquo;t make an effort to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &amp;ldquo;what about blog?&amp;rdquo; you may ask. Yeah, blog also has been in my project list for some time. I always wanted to make a blog project using some of the latest technologies. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with my works and other projects so that blog project has never been started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these days, I tend to develop my own projects with the focus in good quality rather than quantity. After the project is done, I usually put a proper readme file in the GitHub repo. But GitHub repo readme is only suitable for technical aspects (this is just my thought). I want to write down my experiences and challenges. Thus, I decided to make my own blog. Plus, at this point, I have decent experiences and confidence to develop this project.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>