&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>FAQ on HugoPaper</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/tags/faq/</link><description>Recent content in FAQ on HugoPaper</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 20:40:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugopaper.github.io/tags/faq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to use Git Hooks to set Created and Modified Dates</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/setting-dates-via-git-hooks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 20:40:08 +0000</pubDate><author>Simon Smale</author><guid>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/setting-dates-via-git-hooks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I will explain how to use the pre-commit Git hook to automate the input of the created (&lt;code&gt;pubDatetime&lt;/code&gt;) and modified (&lt;code&gt;modDatetime&lt;/code&gt;) in the AstroPaper blog theme frontmatter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents"&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="have-them-everywhere"&gt;Have them Everywhere&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/book/en/v2/Customizing-Git-Git-Hooks"&gt;Git hooks&lt;/a&gt; are great for automating tasks like &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/SSmale/3b380e5bbed3233159fb7031451726ea"&gt;adding&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://itnext.io/using-git-hooks-to-enforce-branch-naming-policy-ffd81fa01e5e"&gt;checking&lt;/a&gt; the branch name to your commit messages or &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/SSmale/367deee757a9b2e119d241e120249000"&gt;stopping you committing plain text secrets&lt;/a&gt;. Their biggest flaw is that client-side hooks are per machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can get around this by having a &lt;code&gt;hooks&lt;/code&gt; directory and manually copy them to the &lt;code&gt;.git/hooks&lt;/code&gt; directory or set up a symlink, but this all requires you to remember to set it up, and that is not something I am good at doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this project uses npm, we are able to make use of a package called &lt;a href="https://typicode.github.io/husky/"&gt;Husky&lt;/a&gt; (this is already installed in AstroPaper) to automatically install the hooks for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update! In AstroPaper &lt;a href="https://github.com/satnaing/astro-paper/releases/tag/v4.3.0"&gt;v4.3.0&lt;/a&gt;, the pre-commit hook has been removed in favor of GitHub Actions. However, you can easily &lt;a href="https://typicode.github.io/husky/get-started.html"&gt;install Husky&lt;/a&gt; yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-hook"&gt;The Hook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we want this hook to run as we commit the code to update the dates and then have that as part of our change we are going to use the &lt;code&gt;pre-commit&lt;/code&gt; hook. This has already been set up by this AstroPaper project, but if it hadn&amp;rsquo;t, you would run &lt;code&gt;npx husky add .husky/pre-commit 'echo &amp;quot;This is our new pre-commit hook&amp;quot;'&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to update dependencies of AstroPaper</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/how-to-update-dependencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 15:33:05 +0000</pubDate><author>Sat Naing</author><guid>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/how-to-update-dependencies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Updating the dependencies of a project can be tedious. However, neglecting to update project dependencies is not a good idea either 😬. In this post, I will share how I usually update my projects, focusing on AstroPaper as an example. Nonetheless, these steps can be applied to other js/node projects as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@/assets/images/forrest-gump-quote.png" alt="Forrest Gump Fake Quote"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents"&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="updating-package-dependencies"&gt;Updating Package Dependencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to update dependencies, and I&amp;rsquo;ve tried various methods to find the easiest path. One way to do it is by manually updating each package using &lt;code&gt;npm install package-name@latest&lt;/code&gt;. This method is the most straightforward way of updating. However, it may not be the most efficient option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommended way of updating dependencies is by using the &lt;a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/npm-check-updates"&gt;npm-check-updates package&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s a good &lt;a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-update-npm-dependencies/"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; from freeCodeCamp about that, so I won&amp;rsquo;t be explaining the details of what it is and how to use that package. Instead, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you my typical approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, install &lt;code&gt;npm-check-updates&lt;/code&gt; package globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;npm install -g npm-check-updates
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before making any updates, it’s a good idea to check all new dependencies that can be updated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;ncu
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the time, patch dependencies can be updated without affecting the project at all. So, I usually update patch dependencies by running either &lt;code&gt;ncu -i --target patch&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;ncu -u --target patch&lt;/code&gt;. The difference is that &lt;code&gt;ncu -u --target patch&lt;/code&gt; will update all the patches, while &lt;code&gt;ncu -i --target patch&lt;/code&gt; will give an option to toggle which package to update. It’s up to you to decide which approach to take.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>