&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Astro on HugoPaper</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/tags/astro/</link><description>Recent content in Astro on HugoPaper</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:11:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugopaper.github.io/tags/astro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to integrate Giscus comments into AstroPaper</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/how-to-integrate-giscus-comments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 11:11:53 +0000</pubDate><author>FjellOverflow</author><guid>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/how-to-integrate-giscus-comments/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hosting a thin static blog on a platform like &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/pages/getting-started-with-github-pages/creating-a-github-pages-site"&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; has numerous advantages, but also takes away some interactivity. Fortunately, &lt;a href="https://giscus.app/"&gt;Giscus&lt;/a&gt; exists and offers a way to embed user comments on static sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="table-of-contents"&gt;Table of contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id="how-giscus-works"&gt;How &lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt; works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/giscus/giscus?tab=readme-ov-file#how-it-works"&gt;Giscus uses the GitHub API&lt;/a&gt; to read and store comments made by &lt;em&gt;GitHub&lt;/em&gt; users in the &lt;code&gt;Discussions&lt;/code&gt; associated with a repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embed the &lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt; client-side script bundle on your site, configure it with the correct repository URL, and users can view and write comments (when logged into &lt;em&gt;GitHub&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach is serverless, as the comments are stored on &lt;em&gt;GitHub&lt;/em&gt; and dynamically loaded from there on client side, hence perfect for a static blog, like &lt;em&gt;AstroPaper&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="setting-up-giscus"&gt;Setting up &lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt; can be set up easily on &lt;a href="https://giscus.app/"&gt;giscus.app&lt;/a&gt;, but I will outline the process shortly still.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="prerequisites"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites to get &lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt; working are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the repository is &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/repositories/managing-your-repositorys-settings-and-features/managing-repository-settings/setting-repository-visibility#making-a-repository-public"&gt;public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href="https://github.com/apps/giscus"&gt;Giscus app&lt;/a&gt; is installed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/github/administering-a-repository/managing-repository-settings/enabling-or-disabling-github-discussions-for-a-repository"&gt;Discussions&lt;/a&gt; feature is turned on for your repository&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any of these conditions cannot be fulfilled for any reason, unfortunately, &lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt; cannot be integrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="configuring-giscus"&gt;Configuring &lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, configuring &lt;em&gt;Giscus&lt;/em&gt; is necessary. In most cases, the preselected defaults are suitable, and you should only modify them if you have a specific reason and know what you are doing. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry too much about making the wrong choices; you can always adjust the configuration later on.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tailwind Typography Plugin</title><link>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/examples/tailwind-typography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 02:05:51 +0000</pubDate><author>Sat Naing</author><guid>https://hugopaper.github.io/post/examples/tailwind-typography/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is from &lt;a href="https://tailwindcss-typography.vercel.app/"&gt;TailwindLabs&lt;/a&gt;. I put this article to demonstrate how you can write blog posts/articles using AstroPaper theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, Tailwind removes all of the default browser styling from paragraphs, headings, lists and more. This ends up being really useful for building application UIs because you spend less time undoing user-agent styles, but when you &lt;em&gt;really are&lt;/em&gt; just trying to style some content that came from a rich-text editor in a CMS or a markdown file, it can be surprising and unintuitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We get lots of complaints about it actually, with people regularly asking us things like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is Tailwind removing the default styles on my &lt;code&gt;h1&lt;/code&gt; elements? How do I disable this? What do you mean I lose all the other base styles too?
We hear you, but we&amp;rsquo;re not convinced that simply disabling our base styles is what you really want. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to remove annoying margins every time you use a &lt;code&gt;p&lt;/code&gt; element in a piece of your dashboard UI. And I doubt you really want your blog posts to use the user-agent styles either — you want them to look &lt;em&gt;awesome&lt;/em&gt;, not awful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;@tailwindcss/typography&lt;/code&gt; plugin is our attempt to give you what you &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; want, without any of the downsides of doing something stupid like disabling our base styles.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>